二零二零年安徽省初中学业水平考试。
短对话理解。
你将听到五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，请在每小题所给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
每段对话读两遍。
1. Hi Bill, your watch is really cool.
Thank you. My uncle gave it to me as a birthday gift last week.
2. People seldom listen to the radio now.
Not really. I usually listen to the radio while I'm driving a
3. Shall we go to the cinema or go shopping this evening?
Sorry, I'm too tired.
I'd like to stay at home.
4. me, does this bus go to the
No, you'll have to get off at number one middle school and take bus number 302.
5. this bus to to the people who go shopping this evening.
5. I am looking for the key to the door.
Could you please carry the bag for me?
Okay, no problem.
I am looking for the key to the door.
Could you please carry the bag for me?
Okay, no problem.
2. Good evening.
二长对话理解。
你将听到两段对话，每段对话后有几个小题，请在每小题所给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
每段对话读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答第六。
是七小题。
Welcome to Chong Cheng Restaurant.
A table for two?
A table for four, please.
We are expecting another two friends.
They will be here at seven o There's half an hour to go.
Would you like to be seated in the corner while waiting?
I'm afraid our friends won't find us if we sit far from the door.
Then what about that table by the window?
Okay, thank you.
Good evening. Welcome to Chong Cheng Restaurant.
A table for two?
A table for four, please.
We are expecting another two friends.
They will be here at seven o There's half an hour to go.
Would you like to be seated in the corner while waiting?
I'm afraid our friends won't find us if we sit far from the door.
Then what about that table by the window?
Okay, thank you.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至十小题。
It's raining again.
The weather report says it will be sunny tomorrow.
Shall we go to the countryside?
Well, I don't want to go out of town.
How about going to the wildlife park?
I went there last week.
Any other ideas?
Why not go to the library?
I want to borrow a book.
idea. What book do you want to borrow?
Journey to the West.
It's full of imagination.
Oh, it's a famous Chinese book.
I watched the TV play years ago, and it interests me so much that I want to read the
book. I also want to read it, because I am interested in Chinese culture.
It's raining again.
weather report says it will be sunny tomorrow.
Shall we go to the countryside?
Well, I don't want to go out of town.
How about going to the wildlife park?
I went there last week.
Any other ideas?
Why not go to the library?
I want to borrow a book.
idea. What book do you want to borrow?
Journey to the West.
It's full of imagination.
Oh, it's a famous Chinese book.
I watched the TV play years ago, and it interests me so much that I want to read the
book. I also want to read it, because I am interested in Chinese culture.
三，短文理解。
你将听到一篇短文，短文后。
有五个小题，请根据短文内容，在每小题所给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
短文读两遍。
C, C, C, C, C, C, C, has been my dream to play on the middle school football team.
I began playing football when I was in grade three.
My elder brother has taught me to play ever since.
He is eight years older than me and good at football.
He practices with me every Wednesday and always attends my games with my parents.
Last month, the middle school football team said they would choose 23 students for
this year's matches.
My brother helped me prepare for the test.
It was held last Saturday.
I worked as hard as I could in the test.
When I was waiting for the team list, I felt nervous.
On Sunday afternoon, I saw my name on the list, and I was excited to be a member of
the team. That evening, my family went out for a big meal to celebrate.
They were proud of me.
It has been my dream to play on the middle school football team.
I began playing football when I was in grade three.
My elder brother has taught me to play ever since.
He is eight years older than me and good at football.
He practices with me every Wednesday and always attends my games with my parents.
Last month, the middle school football team said they would choose 23 students for
this year's matches.
My brother helped me prepare for the test.
It was held last Saturday.
I worked as hard as I could in the test.
When I was waiting for the team list, I felt nervous.
On Sunday afternoon, I saw my name on the list, and I was excited to be a member of
the team. That evening, my family went out for a big meal to celebrate.
They were proud of me.
四信息转。
换，你将听到一篇短文，请根据短文内容写出下面表格中所缺的单词，每
空仅填一词。
短文，读两遍。
Thank you. I'm leaving school.
I'd like to share some ideas about how to deal with my used school things.
First of all, I am going to give my textbooks to my younger sister.
In this way, she can study at home during the summer vacation.
Then, I want to sell my picture books at a low price.
I will give the money to children in poor areas.
Next, the used paper will be taken to the waste center.
As for my notebooks, I decide to keep them for myself because they are part of my
middle school life.
I'm leaving school.
I'd like to share some ideas about how to deal with my used school things.
First of all, I am going to give my textbooks to my younger sister.
In this way, she can study at home during the summer vacation.
Then, I want to sell my picture books at a low price.
I will give the money to children in poor areas.
Next, the used paper will be taken to the waste center.
As for my notebooks, I decide to keep them for myself because they are part of my
middle school life.
Thank you for watching.